In this American English pronunciation video,
在这段美式英语发音视频中，
we're going to learn how to make the N consonant sound.
我们将学习如何发 N 辅音音。
To make this sound,
要发出这个音，
the jaw drops a little,
下巴稍微放低，
and the lips part.
嘴唇分开。
Mm.
嗯。
The front, flat part of the tongue goes to the roof of the mouth.
舌头的前平部分贴到上颚。
Make sure to keep your tongue wide as you do that.
确保在这样做时保持舌头宽。
The soft palate is lowered.
软腭降低。
Air comes up through the nasal passages.
空气通过鼻腔流出。
This makes it a nasal consonant.
这使得它成为一个鼻音辅音。
You can feel the vibration in your nose.
你可以在鼻子里感受到振动。
Mm.
嗯。
There are only three nasal sounds in American English.
美式英语中只有三个鼻音。
Mm,
嗯，
uh,
呃，
mm.
嗯。
It's very important that the tongue be relaxed.
舌头放松是非常重要的。
If there's tension in the back of the tongue,
如果舌头后部有紧张感，
it will sound somewhat like the NG sound, uh,
即使舌头前部在正确的位置，
even if the front of the tongue is in the right position.
听起来也会有点像 NG 音，呃。
One thing that will help relaxation is to think about keeping the tongue really wide.
帮助放松的一个方法是想象保持舌头非常宽。
Mm,
嗯，
mm.
嗯。
Let's look up close and in slow motion.
让我们近距离慢动作观察。
The N sound.
N 音。
Lips relaxed,
嘴唇放松，
tongue wide and lifted to the roof of the mouth.
舌头宽并抬起到上颚。
If you see any darkness on the sides of the tongue when you practice,
如果在练习时看到舌头两侧有任何阴影，
that means there's tension in the tongue.
那意味着舌头有紧张感。
Try to release that tension and keep the tongue wide.
试着释放这种紧张感并保持舌头宽。
The word snag.
单词 snag。
Front of the tongue to roof of mouth.
舌头前部贴到上颚。
The word on.
单词 on。
Wide tongue to the roof of the mouth to finish the word.
宽舌头贴到上颚以完成单词。
The N consonant sound.
N 辅音音。
Know.
Know。
Snag.
Snag。
On.
On。
Example words.
示例单词。
Repeat with me.
跟我重复。
Nice.
Nice。
Nn.
嗯。
Nice.
Nice。
One.
One。
Nn.
嗯。
One.
One。
Number.
Number。
Nn.
嗯。
Number.
Number。
Woman.
Woman。
Nn.
嗯。
Woman.
Woman。
Win.
Win。
Nn.
嗯。
Win.
Win。
Any.
Any。
Nn.
嗯。
Any.
Any。
End.
End。
Nn.
嗯。
End.
End。